# **UX DESIGNER & PRODUCT MANAGER**

# Ana Marija Strmljan

UX/UI designer with a tech and TV journalism background turned product manager. Passionate about creating meaningful high quality tech products.

## strmljan.anamarija@gmail.com

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/anamarijas

Bē https://www.behance.net/strmljananb9bc

## Education

# Certificate in UI Design

April 2018 - September 2018 CareerFoundry, Remote

# Bachelor of Science, Food Science and **Engineering**

October 2012 - September 2016 Biotechnical Faculty, Ljubljana (Slovenia)

## Gymnasium Graduate

September 2005 - June 2009 Gimnazija Sentvid, Ljubljana (Slovenia)

#### Skills

Research

Establishing IA

Wireframing

Prototyping

Figma/Sketch/Adobe XD

Jira/Asana/Trello

**Design Thinking** 

## **Profile**

Coming from a diverse background, I started with a bachelor's in Food Science and Engineering, continued working as a researcher in the biotechnology field and gained experience as a TV journalist. In 2018, I made a shift to UX/UI design. After finishing my design course, I spent some time travelling Asia while working as a UX/UI designer for two excellent digital agencies. Since coming back to Slovenia I've spend more time doing UX and progressed to product management.

## Work Experience

#### UX Designer and Product Manager at Styliff Inc.

September 2019 - Present

Taking ownership of various products and managing their execution from start to finish. Heavily involved in the UX phase of the process.

## UX/UI Designer at Enable Startup Co., Ltd

March 2019 - September 2019

Gathering requirements from clients and transfering them from low fidelity wireframes to full prototypes. Working on various platforms.

## UX/UI Design Intern at 20Scoops Venture Capital GmbH & Co. KG

January 2019 - March 2019

Creating pixel-perfect illustrations, diving into the iOS Human Interface Guidelines and Material Design Guidelines, collaborating on various design projects.

#### TV Journalist at ABCD1 d.o.o.

June 2009 - January 2018

Multi-tasking as a PR officer, marketer, journalist and a TV presenter. Working on branding, audience research and profiling, preparing and organising content.

#### Researcher at IPNA-CSIC

February 2016 - June 2016